<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:24:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>rotDetector</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/code/rotdetector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 16:56:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/code/rotdetector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I built a tool to help keep tech debt in check, make sure feature flags are cleared in a reasonable time and dependencies get updated. Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bigopool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/code/bigopool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 22:15:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/code/bigopool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;high-performance-async-processing-in-go&#34;&gt;High performance async processing in Go&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More on the blog post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/bigopool/&#34;&gt;Bigopool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I built this site no-code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/code/obsidian&#43;hugo-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 21:59:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/code/obsidian&#43;hugo-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge-website-in-an-evening&#34;&gt;The Challenge: Website in an Evening&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a Sunday evening free and decided to see how far I could get building a personal website with an AI agent&amp;rsquo;s help. The goal wasn&amp;rsquo;t just to throw together a basic site, but to create something I&amp;rsquo;d actually want to use - complete with a custom theme, content management, and proper deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert: you&amp;rsquo;re reading this on that very website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-wanted&#34;&gt;What I Wanted&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My requirements were pretty specific:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Long Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-long-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:24:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-long-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s more unsolicited advice to my fellow software engineers anxiously grinding to climb the technical ladder. You may not agree with all of it, but I still invite you to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay Focused and Be Patient&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stop treating your career like a sprint trying to climb faster than your friends. True seniority requires experience acquired through sweat and tears. There&amp;rsquo;s also a massive luck component - right company, right team, right projects, right timing when you interview. Focus on simple principles like learning something new everyday, constantly providing value and being a teammate people actually want to work with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn in Public</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/learn-in-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:24:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/learn-in-public/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s is the first in a series of unsolicited advice to my fellow software engineers grinding to climb the technical ladder. You may not agree with all of them, but I still invite you to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn in Public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contribute to open source projects, join &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; competitions, be active in a programming community. Find ways to work on fun real life problems and build a portfolio along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learning in public does three things simultaneously: it builds your skills working in a complex project/problem instead of tutorial hell, it creates tangible proof of your abilities that goes way beyond a resume, and it puts you in rooms (virtual or otherwise) with people who can change your career trajectory. When you contribute to open source, you&amp;rsquo;re getting code reviews from maintainers who might work at your dream company. And unlike grinding LeetCode in private, everything you do in public compounds - a GitHub contribution from three years ago can still land in a hiring manager&amp;rsquo;s search today. The portfolio you build isn&amp;rsquo;t just code, it&amp;rsquo;s proof you can collaborate, communicate, and ship. Bonus points: You are also making the software engineering world a better place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My challenges with AI assisted coding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:16:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-coding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m very bullish on AI code assistants. It’s actually the second biggest reason I stepped down from being a director and went back to IC life.  I’ll write more about that decision another time, but today I want to share how I’m using AI day-to-day—and, maybe more importantly, when it doesn’t quite fit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My toolkit is pretty simple: VSCode, GitHub Copilot, Claude Sonnet, and occasionally KiloCode.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of working with AI so far has been the waiting. When I’m in “agentic” mode—fire off a big prompt and wait—it kills my flow. If I don’t get an answer in five seconds, my brain is already somewhere else, usually for twice as long as the model took to respond. Because of that, I’ve built my routine around minimizing that problem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Code Rot: How I Built a Tool to Keep Technical Debt in Check</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rotdector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 15:31:37 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rotdector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is a temporary fix. I&amp;rsquo;ll come back for it later&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; – Famous last words that every developer has uttered at least once.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there. You&amp;rsquo;re staring down a deadline, your PM is breathing down your neck, and you need to ship something that works. So you write a quick hack, slap a &lt;code&gt;// TODO: refactor this ugly mess&lt;/code&gt; comment on top, and move on with your life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-performance worker pools with Bigopool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bigopool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 20:45:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bigopool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Concurrency is one of Go&amp;rsquo;s greatest strengths, but managing goroutines effectively at scale can be challenging. When you have millions of tasks to process, spawning a goroutine for each one can quickly overwhelm your system with excessive memory usage and context switching overhead. This is where worker pools come to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I created &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bigodines/bigopool&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bigopool&lt;/a&gt;, a lightweight Go library that implements high-performance worker pools with elegant error and result handling. Today, I have finally decided to write about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Matheus Mendes but most of my friends call me &lt;strong&gt;Bigo&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer with 20 years of professional coding experience, 10 of these working in Silicon Valley startups. I recently bought a cool domain name and decided to start a personal log of projects, advice and interesting stories. I have no intention of updating this more than once or twice a year unless major life events happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 21:58:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a new domain and a goal to write more in 2025 so yeah. Welcome to my website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags:&lt;/strong&gt; #blog&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
