<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:24:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learn in Public</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/learn-in-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:24:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/learn-in-public/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s is the first in a series of unsolicited advice to my fellow software engineers grinding to climb the technical ladder. You may not agree with all of them, but I still invite you to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn in Public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contribute to open source projects, join &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; competitions, be active in a programming community. Find ways to work on fun real life problems and build a portfolio along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learning in public does three things simultaneously: it builds your skills working in a complex project/problem instead of tutorial hell, it creates tangible proof of your abilities that goes way beyond a resume, and it puts you in rooms (virtual or otherwise) with people who can change your career trajectory. When you contribute to open source, you&amp;rsquo;re getting code reviews from maintainers who might work at your dream company. And unlike grinding LeetCode in private, everything you do in public compounds - a GitHub contribution from three years ago can still land in a hiring manager&amp;rsquo;s search today. The portfolio you build isn&amp;rsquo;t just code, it&amp;rsquo;s proof you can collaborate, communicate, and ship. Bonus points: You are also making the software engineering world a better place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handful of lessons - part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/handful-of-lessons---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:24:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/handful-of-lessons---part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a free flow some random unsolicited advice to my fellow software engineers grinding to climb the technical ladder. You may not agree with all of them but I still invite you to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-learn-in-public-contribute-to-open-source-projects-participate-in-kaggle-be-active-in-a-programming-community-find-ways-to-work-in-real-life-problems-and-build-a-portfolio-along-the-way-i-was-lucky-to-be-involved-in-the-early-days-of-joomla-build-a-community-in-brazil-and-make-lifelong-friends-throughout-the-process-that-catapulted-me-to-markets-way-beyond-the-small-town-in-the-country-side-of-brazil-i-was-working-at-the-time-have-i-not-done-that-it-would-take-me-twice-as-long-to-get-to-the-sillicon-valley&#34;&gt;1 Learn in public: contribute to open source projects, participate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;, be active in a programming community. Find ways to work in real life problems and build a portfolio along the way. I was lucky to be involved in the early days of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joomla.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Joomla!&lt;/a&gt;, build a community in Brazil and make lifelong friends throughout the process. That catapulted me to markets way beyond the small town in the country side of Brazil I was working at the time. Have I not done that, it would take me twice as long to get to the Sillicon Valley&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-stay-focused-and-be-patient-career-is-not-a-race-to-advance-it-requires-a-lot-experience-acquired-thought-sweat-and-tears-there-is-also-a-lot-of-luck-involved-right-company-right-team-right-projects-right-time-interviewing-etc-the-beauty-of-it-is-that-i-usually-works-out-in-the-end-i-turned-40-this-year-and-when-i-look-through-my-connections-from-15-or-20-years-ago-they-are-all-doing-very-well-in-life-some-hit-the-jackpot-and-retired-and-the-rest-are-working-in-great-companies-or-have-a-lot-of-fun-building-their-own-companies-some-happier-than-others-in-doing-so-d&#34;&gt;2 Stay focused and be patient. Career is not a race, to advance it requires a lot experience acquired thought sweat and tears. there is also a lot of luck involved (right company, right team, right projects, right time interviewing, etc). The beauty of it is that I usually works out in the end. I turned 40 this year and when I look through my connections from 15 or 20 years ago, they are all doing very well in life. Some hit the jackpot and retired and the rest are working in great companies or have a lot of fun building their own companies (some happier than others in doing so :D)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-in-the-end-the-only-thing-that-matters-is-what-you-and-your-team-deliver-working-software-beats-powerpoints-and-rfcs-a-hacky-v0-solution-this-week-will-beat-a-v1-next-month-98-of-the-time-simply-because-itll-allow-your-company-to-learn-faster&#34;&gt;3 In the end, the only thing that matters is what you and your team deliver. Working software beats powerpoints and RFCs. A hacky v0 solution this week will beat a v1 next month 98% of the time simply because it&amp;rsquo;ll allow your company to learn faster&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;31-software-products-will-never-be-ready-they-might-get-abandoned-tho-software-should-grow-like-a-tree-and-not-like-a-favela-if-you-inherited-a-favela-of-techdebt-you-want-to-improve-one-thing-at-a-time-starting-with-black-box-tests&#34;&gt;3.1 Software products will never be ready (they might get abandoned tho). Software should grow like a tree and not like a favela. If you inherited a favela of techdebt, you want to improve one thing at a time starting with black box tests&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;4-its-your-problem-ive-seen-way-too-many-people-getting-caught--complaining-the-pm-didnt-write-a-proper-jira-tickets-before-sprint-planning-or-that-our-node-version-is-too-old-or-that-standup-meetings-were-taking-too-long-or-that-people-dont-write-tests-at-some-point-youll-sound-like-a-dark-rain-cloud-and-this-prevent-you-from-being-considered-for-exciting-new-opportunities-because-complaining-is-the-easy-route-you-must-be-part-of-the-solution-there-are-probably-already-10-other-people-pointing-to-the-problems&#34;&gt;4 It&amp;rsquo;s your problem. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen way too many people getting caught  complaining the PM didn&amp;rsquo;t write a proper jira tickets before sprint planning. Or that our node version is too old. Or that standup meetings were taking too long. Or that people don&amp;rsquo;t write tests&amp;hellip; At some point you&amp;rsquo;ll sound like a dark rain cloud and this prevent you from being considered for exciting new opportunities because complaining is the easy route. You must be part of the solution, there are probably already 10 other people pointing to the problems&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;5-you-wont-get-promoted-for-doing-expected-work-promotions-need-to-be-justified-you-manager-have-to-have-enough-evidence-to-fight-for-your-case-to-be-promoted-your-performance-must-be-outstanding-sorry-to-break-your-heart-but-the-good-ctos-directors-and-staff-i-know-worked-their-assess-off-specially-in-the-early-days-most-still-dont-do-9-5s&#34;&gt;5 You won&amp;rsquo;t get promoted for doing expected work. Promotions need to be justified, you manager have to have enough evidence to fight for your case. To be promoted your performance must be outstanding. Sorry to break your heart but the good ctos, directors+ and staff+ I know worked their assess off specially in the early days (most still don&amp;rsquo;t do 9-5s)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;51-brag-about-your-work-keep-a-brag-book-or-notes-to-build-a-strong-case-at-the-end-of-the-year-but-also-make-sure-no-one-is-surprised-to-hear-about-what-youve-done-you-work-needs-to-show-off&#34;&gt;5.1 Brag about your work. Keep a Brag Book or notes to build a strong case at the end of the year (but also make sure no one is surprised to hear about what you&amp;rsquo;ve done. You work needs to show off)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;6-if-you-are-not-looking-forward-to-work-on-mondays-quit--for-almost-2-years-i-worked-in-a-place-where-i-didnt-admire-my-manager-and-didnt-really-respect-my-peers-that-was-probably-the-worst-i-could-have-done-to-my-career-and-to-that-company--if-you-are-not-excited-about-your-current-gig-and-you-can-keep-yourself-financially-afloat-for-6-months-leave&#34;&gt;6 If you are not looking forward to work on mondays, quit.  For almost 2 years I worked in a place where I didn&amp;rsquo;t admire my manager and didn&amp;rsquo;t really respect my peers. That was probably the worst I could have done to my career and to that company.  If you are not excited about your current gig and you can keep yourself financially afloat for 6 months, leave&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
